let's look at the solution to our test
and set quiz we have a test and set
instruction that checks the memory
location at the address defined in the
instruction if that location is zero
then we write a one there and set the
register to one if the location is not
zero then we just set the register to
zero without writing to the memory
location and we want to use this to
implement a log function the way we do
that is we set R1 to zero and then as
long as R1 is equal to zero we test and
set lockar and get the result of that
instruction in R1 so what happens is our
R1 starts out at zero so we will enter
this first iteration of the loop if the
test and set finds the lock busy it's
going to read lockware see that it's not
zero returns zero and R1 stays zero and
we keep looping if however the test and
set finds the lockware to be free that
means its memory location is zero then
we do this we set lock V to one thus
changing the state of the lock to locked
and we return one in R1 so that this
Loop will exit so we will only exit this
log function once we acquire the lock
and we will wait here as long as the
lock is not available